Guide to the Administrative Papers of the Chancellor Harry Woodburn Chase 1933-1951 RG.3.0.5
New York University Archives
- Series IV: Adresses and Published Writings
  - Problems in Connection with Junior Colleges," address delivered before the Conference of Trustees of Colleges and Universities, Apr 26, 1935 (Box 78, Folder 9)
  - Address delivered at the Dedication Exercises at Howard University of the Frederick Douglass Memorial, Apr 30, 1935 (Box 78, Folder 10)
  - Proposed Remarks to deliver on receiving the Bronze Bronze Tablets Commemorating Professors Morse and Draper, May 28, 1935 (Box 78, Folder 11)
  - Commencement Address at NYU, Jun 12, 1935 (Box 78, Folder 12)
  - Address delivered at the Dedication of the Nassau College-Hofstra Memorial, Oct 11, 1935 (Box 78, Folder 13)
  - The Outlook for Youth in American Life, address delivered before the International Convention of the YMCA, Oct 26, 1935 (Box 78, Folder 14)
  - Address delivered at the Anti-War Symposium, Nov 8, 1934 (Box 78, Folder 15)
  - Address delivered at the Inauguration of President James at Ohio University, Nov 15, 1935 (Box 78, Folder 16)
  - Remarks delivered at the Dedication Exercises of the Elmer Ellsworth Brown House for English Studies, Dec 2, 1935 (Box 78, Folder 17)
  - Problems and Prospects in Higher Education, address delivered at the First Annual Meeting of the Southern University Conference, Dec 6, 1935 (Box 78, Folder 18)
  - Address delivered before the National Conference on Debtor Relief Laws, Dec 7, 1935 (Box 78, Folder 19)
  - Address delivered at the Dinner in Honor of the Archbishop of York, Dec 16, 1935 (Box 78, Folder 20)
  - Chancellor Chase's Addresses, Correspondence re:, undated (Box 78, Folder 21)
  - Statements of Chancellor Chase, undated (Box 78, Folder 22)
  - Address delivered before the Japan Society, Jan 31, 1936 (Box 78, Folder 23)
  - Should Our Educational System Be Reorganized? address delivered at the Broadcast of the, undated (Box 78, Folder 24)
  - League for Political Education, Feb 6, 1936 (Box 78)
  - Changing Interpretation of Culture, address delivered before the Music Educators, undated (Box 78, Folder 25)
  - National Conference, Mar 30, 1936 (Box 78)
  - The College and the Community, address delivered at the Semi-Centennial Celebration of the, undated (Box 78, Folder 26)
  - University of Chattanooga, Apr 22, 1936 (Box 78)
  - Introductory Remarks delivered at the Presentation of Awards by the National Institute of, undated (Box 78, Folder 27)
  - Immigrant Welfare, May 15, 1936 (Box 78)
  - The University and the Community, address delivered at the Tenth Anniversary Celebration of the American Association of Adult Education, May 19, 1936 (Box 78, Folder 28)
  - Folder Dates, undated (Box 78)
  - The Role of Educational Institutions, address delivered at the Twentieth Annual Meeting of, undated (Box 78, Folder 29)
  - the National industrial Conference Board, Inc., May 28, 1936 (Box 78)
  - Address delivered at the Commencement Exercises of WesleyanCollegeinitsCentennialYear, Jun 1, 1936 (Box 78, Folder 30)
  - Commencement Address at NYU, Jun 10, 1936 (Box 78, Folder 31)
  - Address delivered at the Dedication of Brower Hall at Nassau College-Hofstra Memorial, Oct 9, 1936 (Box 78, Folder 32)
  - The Place of Free Higher Education in American Democracy, address delivered before the Board of Higher Education, Nov 12, 1936 (Box 78, Folder 33)
  - Education Through Current Events, address delivered as the First of a Series of Ten Lectures on Current Events at the Women's University Club, Nov 13, 1936 (Box 79, Folder 1)
  - What is Higher Education? address delivered before the New York Schoolmasters Club, Nov 14, 1936 (Box 79, Folder 2)
  - Address delivered before The Association of University and College Business Officers of the Eastern States, Dec 4, 1936 (Box 79, Folder 3)
  - New Opportunities for Youth, published in Reader's Digest, undated (Box 79, Folder 4)
  - Reflection on 'The Higher Learning in America', an article, undated (Box 79, Folder 5)
  - Statements of Chancellor Chase, undated (Box 79, Folder 6 - 7)
  - The Undergraduate and His World, an unpublished article, undated (Box 79, Folder 8)
  - Address delivered at the Class Agents Dinner of the New York University Alumni, Jan 25, 1937 (Box 79, Folder 9)
  - The American State University, book review publishedintheSaturdayReviewofLiterature, Mar 1937 (Box 79, Folder 10)
  - Remarks delivered at the Dinner in Honor of Dr. Bergmann of the Hebrew University of Jerusalem, Mar 24, 1937 (Box 79, Folder 11)
  - National ecollections: The Foundation of National Character, address delivered at the Dinner of the Museum of the City of New York, Apr 6, 1937 (Box 79, Folder 12)
  - Remarks delivered in Chancellor Chase's capacity as Presiding Officer at the Dinner of the Graduate Faculty of Political Science of the New School for Social Research, Apr 15, 1937 (Box 79, Folder 13)
  - Introductory Remarks delivered at the Presentation of Awards by the National Institute of Immigrant Welfare, Apr 22, 1937 (Box 79, Folder 14)
  - Physical Education and Adult Education, address delivered before the General Session of the Convention of the American Physical Education Association, Apr 23, 1937 (Box 79, Folder 15)
  - Remarks delivered at the Annual Dinner of the National Institute of Social Sciences on the Presentation of a Gold Medal to Dr. John Edgar Hoover, May 11, 1937 (Box 79, Folder 16)
  - Remarks delivered as Toastmaster at the Luncheon on the Tenth Anniversary of the Flight of Colonel Charles Lindbergh, May 20, 1937 (Box 79, Folder 17)
  - Valedictory Address delivered at the One Hundred and Twelfth Commencement of Jefferson Medical College, Jun 4, 1937 (Box 79, Folder 18)
  - Commencement Address at NYU, Jun 9, 1937 (Box 79, Folder 19)
  - Commemoration Address delivered at the Sesqui- Centennial Celebration of Franklin and Marshall College, Oct 15, 1937 (Box 79, Folder 20)
  - The Development of College and University Libraries, address delivered at the New York Times Book Fair, Nov 12, 1937 (Box 79, Folder 21)
  - Address delivered at the Twenty-Ninth Annual National Inter-fraternity Conference, Nov 26, 1937 (Box 79, Folder 22)
  - The American System of Broadcasting, address delivered at The Second National Conference on Educational Broadcasting, Nov 29, 1937 (Box 79, Folder 23)
  - Statements of Chancellor Chase, undated (Box 79, Folder 24)
  - Annual Report of the Chancellor, Draft of, 1938-1939 (Box 80, Folder 1)
  - Twenty Years of Higher Education, reprinted from the Report of the Chancellor for the year 1938-1939 (Box 80, Folder 2)
  - Religion and Democracy, radio address delivered at, undated (Box 80, Folder 3)
  - the Semi-Centennial Celebration of the Jewish Theological Seminary; broadcast over WHN, Jan 11, 1938 (Box 80)
  - Introductory Remarks delivered at the Broadcast for the Script-Writing Classes of NYU; broadcast over WABC, Jan 22, 1938 (Box 80, Folder 4)
  - Address delivered at the Opening of a Series of Broadcasts on the Hall of Fame, Jan 29, 1938 (Box 80, Folder 5)
  - Graduate and Research Work as a Function of the University, address delivered at the Inauguration of Oliver C. Carmichael as Third Chancellor of Vanderbilt University, Feb 4, 1938 (Box 80, Folder 6)
  - Religion and Democracy, radio address delivered on January 11, 1938; published in The American Hebrew, Vol. 142, No. 21, Apr 8, 1938 (Box 80, Folder 7)
  - The Urban University and the Part-Time Student, address delivered on an NBC Broadcast as a portion of the Program on "The Future of Higher Learning in America,", May 3, 1938 (Box 80, Folder 8)
  - Remarks delivered at the Dinner of Tribute to Thomas Mann, May 9, 1938 (Box 80, Folder 9)
  - A Tribute to Leadership, remarks delivered at the Friendship Luncheon for Dean John W. Withers, May 14, 1938 (Box 80, Folder 10)
  - Commencement Address at NYU, Jun 8, 1938 (Box 80, Folder 11)
  - Introductory Remarks delivered at the Dinner in Honor of Lotte Lehmann, Dec 20, 1938 (Box 80, Folder 12)
  - Statements of Chancellor Chase, undated (Box 80, Folder 13)
  - Some Observations on Medical Education, remarks delivered at the Annual Luncheon of the Alumni of the Medical College, Feb 22, 1939 (Box 80, Folder 14)
  - Education for Safety, address delivered at the Tenth Annual Convention of the Greater New York Safety Council., Inc., March 27, 1939; published in Vital Speeches, Vol. V, No. 14, May 1, 1939 (Box 80, Folder 15)
  - Inaugural Address delivered as President of the. Hundred Year Association, Apr 12, 1939 (Box 80, Folder 16)
  - Address delivered at the Twenty-Seventh Convention of the American Association of Collegiate Registrars, Apr 25, 1939 (Box 80, Folder 17)
  - Get Ready for Living Tomorrow, radio address delivered on the Phi Beta Kappa Broadcast at NBC Studios, May 19, 1939 (Box 80, Folder 18)
  - Address delivered at the Formal Opening of the Science and education Exhibits at the New York World's Fair, May 26, 1939 (Box 80, Folder 19)
  - Commencement Address at NYU, Jun 7, 1939 (Box 80, Folder 20)
  - A School Within a School, radio address delivered over the Inter-fraternity Broadcast at NBC Studios, Jun 10, 1939 (Box 80, Folder 21)
  - Address delivered at the Junior-Senior Chapel, Oct 4, 1939 (Box 80, Folder 22)
  - Address delivered on University Day at the University of North Carolina, Oct 12, 1939 (Box 80, Folder 23)
  - Problems for the Future, address delivered at the Twenty-Sixth Annual Meeting of the Association of Urban Universities, Oct 23, 1939 (Box 80, Folder 24)
  - Address delivered at the Memorial Meeting in Honor of Dr. William Hallock Park, Nov 28, 1939 (Box 80, Folder 25)
  - Religion and Youth, address delivered at the Fiftieth Anniversary Dinner of the Inter collegiate Branch of the YMCA, Dec 7, 1939 (Box 80, Folder 26)
  - Behind The Bertrand Russel Case, contains a reprint of a quote made by Chancellor Chase in the New York Times, April 20, 1940, undated (Box 80, Folder 27)
  - Popular Education in America," published in The American Society LegionofHonorMagazine, undated (Box 80, Folder 28)
  - Statements of Chancellor Chase, undated (Box 80, Folder 29)
  - Twenty Years of Higher Education, article based on excerpts from the 1938-1939 Annual Report of the Chancellor; published in What The Colleges Are Doing, No. 57, Jan 1940 (Box 80, Folder 30)
  - Acknowledgement Address delivered at the Dinner of the Coat and Suit Industry for the Distribution of the Fund Raised for Refugee Relief, Jan 31, 1940 (Box 80, Folder 31)
  - Youth and Society," address delivered at the Annual Regional Conference on Social Hygiene, Feb 7, 1940 (Box 80, Folder 32)
  - Address delivered at the Seventieth Anniversary Dinner of the Lotos Club, Mar 30, 1940 (Box 81, Folder 1)
  - Memorial Address delivered in Commemoration of Dr. John Huston Finley in the Great Hall of the College of the City of New York, Apr 14, 1940 (Box 81, Folder 2)
  - Youth and Society, address delivered at the Banquet of the New York State Medical Society, May 7, 1940 (Box 81, Folder 3)
  - Commencement Address at NYU, Jun 2, 1940 (Box 81, Folder 4)
  - Commencement Address at Lehigh University, Jun 10, 1940 (Box 81, Folder 5)
  - Address delivered at Graduation Exercises Celebrating the Eightieth Anniversary of The Women's Law Class of NYU, Jun 13, 1940 (Box 81, Folder 6)
  - The Disciplines of Democracy, address delivered on June 10, 1940; published in Vital Speeches, Vol. VI, No. 18, Jul 1, 1940 (Box 81, Folder 7)
  - The Student in Selective Service, radio address broadcast over CBS, sponsored by the American Council on Education, Oct 8, 1940 (Box 81, Folder 8)
  - Italian Contributions to American Life, address delivered at the Columbus Day Celebration at the American Common at the New York World's Fair, Oct 12, 1940 (Box 81, Folder 9)
  - Address delivered at the Alumni Fund Agents' Dinner, Oct 22, 1940 (Box 81, Folder 10)
  - Address delivered at the Fiftieth Anniversary Dinner of the New York Schoolmasters Club, Nov 9, 1940 (Box 81, Folder 11)
  - College Men and Conscription, article printed in The Delta; published by Sigma Nu Fraternity, Vol. 58, No.2, Dec 1940 (Box 81, Folder 12)
  - Statements of Chancellor Chase, undated (Box 81, Folder 13)
  - Youth and Democracy, guest editorial published in The American Farm Youth, Vol. VI, No. 8, Jan 1941 (Box 81, Folder 14)
  - Radio address delivered at the Luncheon of The American College Publicity Association, broadcast over WNYC, Jan 25, 1941 (Box 81, Folder 15)
  - National Self-Preservation, address delivered at the Meeting of the Economic Club of New York, Feb 10, 1941 (Box 81, Folder 16)
  - Academic Freedom and Freedom of the Press, address delivered on January 25, 1941; published in Vital Speeches, Vol. VII, No. 9, Feb 15, 1941 (Box 81, Folder 17)
  - National Preservation, address delivered on February 10, 1941; published in Vital Speeches, Vol. VII, No. 10, Mar 1, 1941 (Box 81, Folder 18)
  - Address delivered at the Centennial Dinner of the New York University College of Medicine, Mar 21, 1941 (Box 81, Folder 19)
  - The Relation of Universities to Business, address delivered at the Life Underwriters' Association Dinner, Jun 5, 1941 (Box 81, Folder 20)
  - Commencement Address at NYU, Jun 8, 1941 (Box 81, Folder 21)
  - Address delivered at the Fordham Centenary Dinner, Sep 16, 1941 (Box 81, Folder 22)
  - Agencies of Enlightenment, reprinted -from address delivered to The American College Publicity Association, January 25, 1941, Oct 1941 (Box 81, Folder 23)
  - Address delivered at the Dinner of the Committee on Planned Parenthood Celebrating the Twenty-Fifth Anniversary of the Birth Control Federation of American, Oct 16, 1941 (Box 81, Folder 24)
  - Address delivered at the Class Day Exercises of the EveningDivisionoftheCollegeofEngineering, Oct 25, 1941 (Box 81, Folder 25)
  - Statements of Chancellor Chase, undated (Box 82, Folder 1)
  - Address delivered at the Arts and Engineering Dinner, Feb 10, 1942 (Box 82, Folder 2)
  - Address delivered at the Seventy-Fifth Anniversary Dinner of the College of Dentistry, Mar 19, 1942 (Box 82, Folder 3)
  - New-International concepts, address delivered at the Seventeenth Annual Meeting of the American Association for Adult Education, May 11, 1942 (Box 82, Folder 4)
  - Commencement Address at NYU, June 7, 1942 (Box 82, Folder 5)
  - Flag Day Address, radio address broadcast over WNYC, Jun 15, 1942 (Box 82, Folder 6)
  - Presidential Address, reprinted from address delivered on May 11, 1942; published in the Adult Education Journal, Vol. 1, No. 3, Jul 1942 (Box 82, Folder 7)
  - Address delivered at the Inauguration of Dr. George D. Stoddard as Commissioner of Education in the University of the State of New York, Oct 16, 1942 (Box 82, Folder 8)
  - Remarks delivered at the Dinner for Nobel Prize Winners sponsored by the Common Council for American Unity, Dec 10, 1942 (Box 82, Folder 9)
  - Statements of Chancellor Chase, undated (Box 82, Folder 10)
  - Edison, The Inventor, radio address delivered over WOR for the Thomas A. Edison Birthday Program, Feb 11, 1943 (Box 82, Folder 11)
  - Remarks broadcast over WBNX for Brotherhood Week 'Program, Feb 19, 1943-Feb 26, 1943 (Box 82, Folder 12)
  - Commencement Address at University of North Carolina, Mar 14, 1943 (Box 82, Folder 13)
  - Address delivered at the Fifth Pan-European Conference, Mar 27, 1943 (Box 82, Folder 14)
  - Remarks delivered at the Tribute Luncheon in Honor of Mr. Charles H. Tuttle, Apr 1, 1943 (Box 82, Folder 15)
  - Keynote Address before the Twenty-Sixth Convention of the American College Publicity Association, May 6, 1943 (Box 82, Folder 16)
  - Commencement Address at NYU, Jun 9, 1943 (Box 82, Folder 17)
  - Universities and Postwar Planning, printed in After the War; published by the Institute on Postwar Reconstruction, Vol. 1, No. 4, Oct 1943 (Box 82, Folder 18)
  - Address delivered at the Opening Conference of the Women's Council for Post War Europe, Oct 20, 1943 (Box 82, Folder 19)
  - The Higher Education in Postwar America, published in The American Mercury, undated (Box 82, Folder 20)
  - Statements of Chancellor Chase, undated (Box 82, Folder 21)
  - Remarks delivered at the Opening of the Symposium on Medical Education in Relation to the Practice of Medicine of the Future, Jan 17, 1944 (Box 82, Folder 22)
  - Commencement Address at NYU, Jun 7, 1944 (Box 82, Folder 23)
  - Remarks delivered at the Army Safety Program Dinner and Conference, undated (Box 82, Folder 24)
  - Colleges in Postwar America, published in The American Mercury, Jul 1944 (Box 82, Folder 25)
  - Address delivered at the Medical College Alumni Dinner Honoring Doctors Samuel A. Brown and George B. Wallace, Oct 26, 1944 (Box 82, Folder 26)
  - The Dental College Today, published in the New York University Dental Journal, Dec 1944 (Box 82, Folder 27)
  - Address delivered at the Nobel Award Dinner, Dec 10, 1944 (Box 82, Folder 28)
  - Statements of Chancellor Chase, undated (Box 83, Folder 1)
  - Education for Peace, address delivered before The Friends of Democracy, Jan 18, 1945 (Box 83, Folder 2)
  - The Education of Youth for Participation in the Changing World, address delivered before the Meeting of the New York Academy of Public Education, Feb 20, 1945 (Box 83, Folder 3)
  - Remarks delivered at the Dedication (?) of Dean Thomas M. Balliet Teachers' Library, Gift of Professor Paul Radosavljevich, Mar 22, 1945 (Box 83, Folder 4)
  - Some Thoughts on Postwar Education, address delivered at the Annual Luncheon of the School of Education Alumni, Apr 21, 1945 (Box 83, Folder 5)
  - Commencement Address at NYU, Jun 13, 1945 (Box 83, Folder 6)
  - Suggested Draft of Remarks for use at the Welfare Council Dinner, Oct 3, 1945 (Box 83, Folder 7)
  - Remarks made at the Luncheon of the American Scandinavian Foundation, Nov 3, 1945 (Box 83, Folder 8)
  - Address delivered at the Hall of Residence Dinner for the Medical College Campaign-Mr. Levin's Project, Dec 4, 1945 (Box 83, Folder 9)
  - Statements of Chancellor Chase, undated (Box 83, Folder 10)
  - Commencement Address at NYU, Jun 12, 1946 (Box 83, Folder 11)
  - Remarks delivered at the Opening Dinner of the Medical Center Campaign, Oct 21, 1946 (Box 83, Folder 12)
  - Statements of Chancellor Chase, undated (Box 83, Folder 13)
  - Address delivered: Luncheon for the New York York University-Bellevue Medical Center Campaign Leaders, January 22, 1947 (Box 83, Folder 14)
  - Remarks delivered at the Fifty-Ninth Annual Dinner of the NYU Law Alumni Association, March 10, 1947 (Box 83, Folder 15)
  - Commencement Address at NYU, Jun 11, 1947 (Box 83, Folder 16)
  - Address delivered at the Commerce and Industry Division Dinner, NYU-Bellevue Medical Center Campaign, Sep 30, 1947 (Box 83, Folder 17)
  - Statements of Chancellor Chase, undated (Box 83, Folder 18)
  - Remarks delivered at the Sixtieth Annual NYU Law Alumni Association Dinner, Feb 10, 1948 (Box 83, Folder 19)
  - Remarks delivered in a Panel Discussion at the Dedication of the Sloan-Kettering Institute for Cancer Research of Memorial Hospital, Apr 16, 1948 (Box 83, Folder 20)
  - Address delivered at the Annual Dinner of the New York Academy of Public Education, May 18, 1948 (Box 83, Folder 21)
  - Commencement Address at NYU, Jun 9, 1948 (Box 83, Folder 22)
  - Remarks delivered at the Testimonial Dinner in Honor of U.S. Court of Appeals Judge Florence E. Allen, Nov 8, 1948 (Box 83, Folder 23)
  - Statements of Chancellor Chase, undated (Box 83, Folder 24)
  - Remarks delivered at the Sixty-First Annual NYU Law Alumni Association Dinner in Honor of Chief Justice Arthur T. Vanderbilt, Feb 10, 1949 (Box 83, Folder 25)
  - Commencement Address at NYU, Jun 15, 1949 (Box 83, Folder 26)
  - Statements of Chancellor Chase, undated (Box 83, Folder 27)
  - Remarks delivered at the One Hundred and Twenty Fifth Anniversary Celebration of the National Academy of Design, Jan 17, 1950 (Box 83, Folder 28)
  - Address at the Dinner Celebrating the Fiftieth Anniversary of the School of Commerce, Accounts and Finance, Apr 11, 1950 (Box 83, Folder 29)
  - Commencement Address at NYU, Jun 14, 1950 (Box 83, Folder 30)
  - Remarks delivered at the Ceremonies Marking the Inauguration of Gordon Gray as President of the University of North Carolina, Oct 10, 1950 (Box 83, Folder 31)
  - Statements of Chancellor Chase, undated (Box 83, Folder 32)
  - Remarks delivered at the Dinner Given in Chancellor Chase's Honor Upon His Retirement, Jan 24, 1951 (Box 83, Folder 33)
  - Commencement Address at Hofstra College, Jun 10, 1951 (Box 83, Folder 34)
  - Miscellaneous Clippings 1938-52 Chase HW, undated (Box 83, Folder 35)
  - Certificate of appointment of Chase to Mayors Business Advisory Committee, signed by Mayor Fiorello LaGuardia (Oversize Case II, Drawer 12, left), 1940 (Box Case II, Folder Drawer 12)
  - Bound volumes: Addresses of Harry Woodburn Chase, 1934-1945 (Box 84, Box 85)